What's wrong with you?
You haven't answered my emails.
I can't tell you now.
Yes, you can.
Who is the caveman?
The man Grandfather wanted me to find.
You can't bring him in like that.
Yashida-sama.
Kuzuri.
- Please, father!
- Quiet!
Wait, father.
Please, listen to me.
Not now, Mariko.
- Plese, listen to me, Dad.
- Stop bothering me!
- Please, listen to me.
- I have no time for this.
- You must hear what Grandfather told me.
- I told you, shut up!
You just don't care!
That's why grandfather...
Don't look so sad, Shingen.
I'm still dying.
There is no easy way to say this.
But then, it's never been
easy for us, has it?
I have tried, father.
You've done the best you can.
You're not making sense, Father...
That will never happen.
Kuzuri.
This cowardly attack was...
the work of Yakuza thugs.
A violent response to my efforts...
to crack down on organized crime.
They exited the North Gate.
She was with the stranger--
Our island is long and thin.
Trains only run in two directions.
I assure you Lord Shingen...
my officers are making every effort--
Then they're idiots.
You've wasted enough of my time.
I have my father's affairs to attend to.
Get out and find her!
If the Yakuza got
into the funeral...
they had someone inside.
They'll never find me here.
You're not safe.
I'm coming down there.
They'll follow you.
Please.
Wait a few days.
Please. I'm fine.
Logan's here.
He's wounded, Mariko.
Someone's here.
I have to go.
A tree fell on the road.
The men could use some help.
Kuzuri.
Come on!
Did you know I studied
biology in college?
Genetics.
There are genes that skip generations.
Recessive genes.
Eyes.
Eyes. Hair.
Talent.
Temperament.
Not every child gets the same.
My father saw little of himself in me.
But in you...
he faced a mirror.
How did you convince my father...
to award you control...
of Asia's largest corporation?
You've gone insane.
I'm just waking up.
If you kill me, you will lose...
what little honor you have left.
I don't want to hurt you.
I want to help you.
Help you end your pain...
what that mutant stopped you...
from doing last week.
I never wanted to die, Father.
You are my only family.
Be well, sister.