Have some tea.
It'll help you to recover.
Old lady found you
lying in the river.
We all thought you were dead.
Let's go! Let's go!
Running away?
Help me!
Please let her go!
Quick, go and grab hold
of that guy!
Stop, stop!
Drop what you are holding!
Try to run and I'll kill you.
Come here!
What is that you are holding?
Where are you from?
Drop the staff if you want your life.
Please Sirs, some money
to this poor drunkard.
Get lost!
Where did you get that staff?
Where did you find it?
Cheers!
Old wife.
Where did this come from?
From them.
Officers, look what they're using to pay.
What is this?
My Lord
How dare you...
can't you see I am busy?
The devine staff of legend...
It was seen in the Middle Kingdom...
Impossible.
The villagers are beginning to
whisper of prophecy...
Mortals are always whispering of prophecy.
It's their opium.
What other offending news
do you have for me?
That is all, My Lord.
Summon the Witch...
The one born of wolves.
Where were we?
He's not even Chinese.
We are all the same inside,
Aren't we Monk?
Heaven help us.
What, you find it a sin?
Yes, it is sinful not to share.
Cheers!
An old man and a boy,
They had tea here, Yes?
A Soldier Monk rides with them...
Who else?
I do not know
who you speak of...
Men are such liars.
Sparrow...
...where do you nest?
Horse Stance!
It is them.
They're headed towards the desert.
They are between me and the River of Sand.
Isn't it just like King Monkey...
...summoning a boy to do a man's job?
Cheers!