Credits to McGarrett - www.addic7ed.com
Alien-Only subtitles
Resynced by pope3909 - www.iptorrents.com
11/2017 - VLC 2.2.6
Good morning.
Stay here.
- Good morning.
Good morning.
Let's go on.
- Good morning.
Good morning.
Let us give back to nature
what she gave to us.
Give this pearl to my daughter,
Princess Laho.
What is that?
Fast shelter!
Come on, quickly!
- What happened?
- There are objects falling from the sky.
Oh my goodness...
Secure all people,
bring them to a safe place.
Come on, hurry.
Wait.
Dolark!
They are coming.
Quickly, take cover!
- Wait...
- Come on!
- All gather!
- Faster!
- Come on, quickly!
- Come on.
It's broken!
Aksha!
No!
I'm sorry.
- No!
- Please.
No!
Goodbye.
[Angry rambling]
Quiet.
Quiet!