TRON: I don't like it when you cut it this close.
KEVIN: Will you stop worrying, Tron?
Everything's just fine.
- Everything's under control.
- CLU: Flynn!
Am I still to create the perfect system?
Yeah.
TRON: Go.
TRON: Flynn go!
(TRON YELLS)
Good evening. Our lead story.
ENCOM CEO and video game icon
Kevin Flynn has disappeared.
He was best known for designing Tron
and Space Paranoids,
the two bestselling video games
in history.
Flynn took ownership of ENCOM
in 1982
as the company skyrocketed
to the top of the tech industry.
But things changed in 1985
with the untimely death of Flynn's wife,
the mother of his young son, Sam.
Recently, ENCOM board members
have been troubled by reports
of Flynn's erratic,
even obsessive, behavior.
With Flynn missing,
the company is now in chaos.
This afternoon, ENCOM's board
moved to seize control
from Flynn's partner, Alan Bradley,
vowing to return the company
to profitability.
Loyal to the end, Bradley maintains
his belief that Flynn is not missing
and is instead pursuing his dream of
"a digital frontier
to reshape the human condition."
TV: Even Flynn's
most ardent supporters
are now acknowledging a difficult truth.
Kevin Flynn may have simply
run away.
And while Flynn's loyalists
hope for his imminent return,
there is perhaps no one who wishes it
to happen more than young Sam Flynn,
now in the care of his grandparents,
and heir to an empire in turmoil.
SAM: He's coming. He promised.
- Sam, you have to eat.
- Let go of me!
Sam?
What will become of Flynn's legacy
and the future of ENCOM
will most likely depend
on what becomes of this
now orphaned little boy.
GRANDMOTHER: Sam! Come back!
RADIO: All cycle units, stand by.
(SIREN)
(SIGHS)
Why are you in my apartment, Alan?
You don't answer your phone.
- How you been, Sam?
- Oh, you know,
when I was 12, I appreciated
the surrogate-father thing. But come on.
I got it all under control now.
Oh. Clearly!
You want to help me
with my homework?
Like old times? Have a catch?
Alan, are we really
going to do this again?
Do I really look like I'm ready
to run a Fortune 500 company?
No.
Truthfully...
I was paged last night.
Oh, man, still rocking the pager?
(LAUGHS) Good for you.
Yeah, your dad once told me
I had to sleep with it, and I still do.
Page came from your dad's office
at the arcade.
- So?
That number's been disconnected
for 20 years.
Sam, two nights before he disappeared,
he came to my house.
"I've cracked it," he kept saying.
He wouldn't have left that, Sam.
He wouldn't have left you.
Oh, Alan. You're the only one
who still believes that.
He's either dead
or chilling in Costa Rica.
Here.
These are the keys to the arcade.
I haven't gone over there yet.
I thought you should be the one.
Alan, you're acting like I'm gonna
find him sitting there working.
Just, "Hey, kiddo. Lost track of time."
Wouldn't that be something?
- (DOG YELPS)
- What?
(WHINES)
(BARKS)
(DOOR CREAKS)
(MACHINES BEEP AND WHOOSH)
(ROCK MUSIC BLARES)
(SONG CONTINUES
IN THE DISTANCE)
(SONG FINISHES)
(MUSIC BOOMS IN THE DISTANCE)
(SONG CONTINUES
IN THE DISTANCE)
You son of a gun.
Flynn.
Huh.
Let's try the back door.
What were you working on?
LaserControl.
Okay.
(BEEPING)
(WHIRRING)
(GASPS)
(WHOOSHING)
This isn't happening.
(WIND WHISTLES)
This is happening.
No disk.
Another stray.
Hey, wait.
Wait!
MAN: Not the games, not the games,
not the games, not the games...
(GROWLS)
Rectify.
- Games.
- No. Please!
Rectify.
You probably get this a lot,
but there's been a big mistake.
Games.
- Please, no, no.
- Whoa. Hey.
No! Erase me!
(SCREAMS)
No! Wait! Wait!
(BEEPING)
COMPUTER: Attention, program.
You will receive an identity disk.
Everything you do or learn
will be imprinted on this disk.
If you lose your disk,
you will be subject to de-resolution.
Mirroring complete.
Proceed to games.
SAM: Games?
Where are you going?
What am I supposed to do?
Survive.
(CROWD ROARS)
COMPUTER: All combatants,
prepare for disk wars.
CROWD: Disk wars! Disk wars!
Disk wars!
(ALL CHEER)
COMPUTER: Platform 8.
Combatants 3 and 11.
Disk wars.
(SCREAMS)
(CROWD CHEERS)
COMPUTER: Combatant 11.
De-resolution.
I won!
Now let me out!
Combatant 3, round one, victory.
No unusual activity on the Grid.
Security sweeps and patrols
have been intensified.
Rectifier on schedule.
Your initiative should be
fully operational within 12 cycles.
Combatants 3 and 7, disk wars.
Initiate.
(GROWLS)
I'm out.
(CROWD CHEERS)
(GASPS)
Combatant 3, victory.
Combatant 3, violation.
(SCREAMS)
Combatant 6, de-resolution.
What is that program?
Combatant 3,
violation.
(BEEPING)
Initiate final round.
Combatant 3 versus Rinzler.
CROWD: Rinzler!
Rinzler!
You gotta be kidding me.
(CROWD CHEERS)
Come on, is that even legal?
(GROANS)
(YELLS)
CROWD: De-rez!
De-rez!
User.
(CROWD BOOS)
Identify yourself, program.
- I'm not a program.
- (CROWD BOOS)
My name is Sam Flynn.
(CROWD FALLS SILENT)
Bring him to me.
Where am I?
Who are you?
Dad.
Sam.
Look at you, man.
Look at the size of you.
- How did you get in here?
- I got your message.
Oh. So it's just you?
Yeah.
Just you. Oh. (LAUGHS)
Isn't this something?
You look the same.
A lot's happened, Sam.
More than you can imagine. Disk.
Let's have a look.
(SAM LAUGHS)
Got it.
Hmm. I expected more.
So, you were trapped in here.
That's right.
- And you're in charge.
- Right again. You're two for two.
So can we just go home now?
Not in the cards.
Not for you.
That's a hell of a way to treat your son.
Oh, that.
I'm not your father, Sam.
But I'm very, very happy to see you.
Where is he?
What did you do to him?
Same thing I'm going to do to you.
User.
- Greetings, programs.
- (CROWD CHEERS)
Oh, what an occasion
we have here before us.
Because your rumors are true.
We do indeed have in our midst
a user!
(CROWD BOOS)
A user.
So, what to do?
What does this user deserve?
Might I suggest perhaps...
the challenge of the Grid?
(CROWD CHEERS)
And who best to battle
this singular opponent?
Perhaps one who has some
experience in these matters.
(CROWD ROARS)
Oh, yes, indeed, programs.
Your liberator!
Your luminary!
Your leader and maker!
The one who vanquished
the tyranny of the user
those many cycles before!
CLU: I've been waiting
a long time for this.
JARVIS: Clu!
You wanna play, I'll play.
What's this?
What do I do with this?
I'll give you a hint.
Not that.
COMPUTER: Grid is live.
Initiate light cycle battle.
You got no chance, user.
Their bikes are faster than ours.
Use the levels.
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
Hey!
We gotta work together.
Boo!
(SCREAMS)
- Whoo-hoo!
- Yeah!
That's what I'm talking about!
Let's go!
Hang on, buddy, I'm coming.
Come on.
(LAUGHS)
This is it. Come on.
(CROWD CHEERS)
(CROWD BOOS)
Illegal combatant on the Grid.
Get in.
Get in!
System failure. Release Rinzler.
Game on, old friend.
- Who are you?
- Hang on.
(SCREAMS)
You can't make that!
DRIVER: Made it.
I'm Quorra.
Their vehicles can't go off Grid.
They'll malfunction on this terrain.
- What about us?
- (LAUGHS) Obviously not.
- Where are you taking me?
- Patience, Sam Flynn.
All your questions
will be answered soon.
Wait here.
MAN: Quorra.
I dreamed.
First time in years.
QUORRA: It's a sign.
(MAN LAUGHS)
MAN: A sign, my dear apprentice,
of a weary soul.
MAN: I'm afraid something's happened.
QUORRA: Something has happened.
We have a guest.
MAN: There are no guests, kiddo.
Sam...
You're here.
I'm here.
(SIGHS)
You're big.
You're...
Old.
(CHUCKLES)
KEVIN: How did you get here?
Alan came over.
Bradley.
Yeah. He got your page.
I found your office under the arcade.
Page...
Oh, the page.
Of course.
Clu had him on the light cycle grid.
I intervened.
Oh.
Dinner soon.
We'll talk then.
He never thought he'd see you again.
Yeah.
Vintage.
It doesn't get out as much
as it used to, but...
QUORRA: Do you know it?
His patience usually beats out
my more aggressive strategy.
Flynn shared them with me.
I've read them all.
Oh. Light reading.
Tolstoy.
Dostoyevsky.
I-Ching. Journey Without Goal.
Must have a killer ending.
Flynn is teaching me
about the art of the selfless,
about removing oneself
from the equation.
But between you and me,
Jules Verne is my favorite.
Your move, Flynn, come on.
Come on!
(CUTLERY CLINKS)
QUORRA: How old are you now, Sam?
KEVIN: You should be 27.
SAM: Yes, 27.
QUORRA: Do you attend a college?
SAM: Caltech.
Caltech. My alma mater.
SAM: Yeah.
Till I dropped out.
(QUORRA LAUGHS)
Work?
- KEVIN: Job? ENCOM? Are you...
- No.
I check in once a year.
- Wife, girlfriend?
- Dog.
Marvin.
KEVIN: Well, dogs...
Dogs are cool.
I'm sure you must have
a few questions of your own, Sam.
Actually, just one.
Why I never came home.
Those nights when I went to the office,
I'm sure you've figured it out by now,
I was coming here.
Human form into digital space.
Heavy stuff.
But... I needed partners to help out.
I brought Tron here to protect this system.
Clu was my creation,
designed to create a perfect world.
We were jamming, man,
building utopia.
Hours in here were just
minutes back home.
Just when I thought
it couldn't get any more profound,
something unexpected happened.
ISOs. Isomorphic algorithms.
- A whole new life form.
- And you created them?
(LAUGHS)
No. No.
They manifested, like a flame.
They weren't really from anywhere.
The conditions were right
and they came into being.
I found them in here.
Like flowers in a wasteland.
They were spectacular.
Everything I'd hoped to find
in the system,
control, order, perfection,
none of it meant a thing.
I'd been living in a hall of mirrors.
SAM: So what happened?
KEVIN: Clu. Clu happened.
KEVIN: Tron, he fought for me.
I never saw him again.
Clu saw the ISOs as an imperfection.
So he destroyed them.
(DISTANT SCREAMING)
"The Purge."
- He killed them all?
- It was genocide.
I tried to get back
but I couldn't get to the portal.
It closed on me, Sam.
That's why I never came home.
SAM: So the portal...
It's open now.
KEVIN: Not for long.
Only one millicycle, about eight hours.
So we go now. Go home.
We make a run for it.
- We get you out of here.
- Don't rush.
What do you mean?
The portal's gonna close.
What? What is it?
The moment Flynn is on the Grid, Clu
will stop at nothing to obtain his disk.
Clu figures if I can be in...
SAM: He can be out?
KEVIN: With my disk, it's possible.
SAM: And then what?
Game over.
The guy doesn't dig imperfection.
So what do we do? Nothing?
It's amazing how productive
doing nothing can be.
Clu's planning something.
We've known that for a while.
Programs have been disappearing.
There's unrest out there,
even revolution.
If we sit tight, Clu might
be brought down from the inside.
SAM: If the portal is closing, we can't
sit around. We have to move now.
Tell me, what brought you here,
to the Grid?
Alan got your page.
I didn't send any page.
It was Clu.
Clu sent that page.
That's why you're here.
This is all his design.
He wanted a new piece
on the board to change the game!
With you, he got more
than he ever dreamed.
This is precisely what he wants.
Us together heading for the portal.
It's his game now.
The only way to win is not to play.
Well, that's a hell of a way to live.
Goodnight, Sam.
How can he be so afraid
of his own creation?
I mean, he built Clu.
Why doesn't he just end him?
He could,
but it would require reintegration.
Yeah, all right.
Flynn would never survive the event.
It would mean the end of them both.
I'm going through the portal.
Clu wants Flynn's disk, not mine.
I'm going to find Alan and we'll figure
this thing out from the other side.
This may be Clu's game here, but
in my world, he's gone in one keystroke.
But I can't do anything
unless I get to the portal.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
There's someone I once knew,
a program named Zuse
who fought alongside the ISOs.
They say he can get anyone anywhere.
SAM: How do I find him?
QUORRA: This is his sector.
Make it there alive, and he'll find you.
(SEAGULLS CRY IN THE DISTANCE)
Sam?
COMPUTER: All programs are required
to present identity disks
at city checkpoints.
Any program in violation of their
function is subject to termination.
FEMALE VOICE: Sam Flynn?
You remember me?
- Yeah. You gave me some advice.
- And you followed it.
It's unfortunate we met the way we did.
You have a good night.
You're looking for someone.
What makes you say that?
Intuition.
Sir, the sentries downtown
have recovered Flynn's light cycle.
We've traced it to its point of origin.
KEVIN: Prepare the light runner,
Quorra.
We're going downtown.
QUORRA: Flynn!
You don't need to go.
I've sent him to someone we can trust.
Quorra, there is no choice.
I won't lose him again.
- (LIVELY CHATTER)
- (POUNDING MUSIC)
Relax. They're occupied.
(LAUGHTER)
His name is Castor. If you want to speak
to Zuse, you need to go through him.
CASTOR: Where's your sense of humor,
my friend?
We shall see.
I brought your boy Flynn.
If you'll excuse me for a moment,
I have to attend to something.
But have a drink,
courtesy of the End of Line Club!
Come, away from
these primitive functions.
The son of Flynn.
Of all the innumerable possibilities,
he has to walk into mine.
Libations
for everybody!
(CHEERING)
I'm Castor, your host.
Provider of any and all entertainments
and diversions.
At your service.
I'm looking for Zuse.
Indeed. Many are.
Where can I find him?
This, pretty miss, is a conversation
best had behind closed doors.
Perhaps we should retire
to my private lounge.
I designed it myself, you know. It's true.
I'm stepping away for a moment, boys.
Change the scheme, alter the mood.
- (LIVELY MUSIC)
- Thank you.
Gem. My name is Gem.
(GROWLS)
(LAUGHS)
KEVIN - You are Clu.
CLU - I am Clu.
KEVIN - You will create the perfect system.
CLU - I will create the perfect system.
(CHANDELIER TINKLES)
KEVIN - Together we're gonna
change the world, man.
(ROARS)
(LAUGHS)
(SIGHS)
Let's move.
CASTOR: Zuse has been around
since the earliest days
of the gaming grid.
By necessity,
he has to mind all the percentages.
All the angles.
So when do I meet him?
You just did.
(LAUGHS)
After the Purge,
I needed to reinvent myself.
Self-preservation, you understand.
Now, what can I do for you?
I need to get to the portal.
Well, it's closing quickly,
as I'm sure you're aware.
Tick-tock, tick-tock.
And it's quite the journey.
Beyond the far reaches of the Outlands.
- Can you help me?
- Of course.
But first, as a man who prides himself
on staying well informed,
I must ask who sent you my way.
Her name's Quorra.
Said she met you a long time ago.
Indeed she did.
Many cycles ago.
It was a different time.
But we're not here to relive the past.
Let's see about your future, shall we?
We'll have to change your attire
and you'll need a forged disk.
Not easy these days.
And of course you'll need transport
to cross the Sea of Simulation.
This is going to be quite the ride.
(SCREAMING)
I believed in users once before.
The game has changed, son of Flynn!
(CACKLES)
I met your friend. He's fantastic!
Behold! The son of our maker!
(LAUGHS)
Yeah, yeah!
(GROANS)
(MUSIC STOPS)
Go, go!
Let's split, man.
(BEEPS)
(SCREAMING)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
SAM: Your disk.
Dad, it's gone.
It is.
I'm sorry. I know I messed up.
We can go back.
- I can go back.
- No, we stay together.
- Dad, I can do this.
- You've done enough already!
SAM: So what do we do now?
You ever jump a freight train?
Huh?
We do it your way.
Full-on sprint to the portal.
If we beat Clu there, we have a chance.
Let's get her out of here.
- Is she gonna make it?
- I don't know.
I've got to identify the damaged code.
The sequencing
is just enormously complex.
- SAM: But didn't you write it?
- Some of it. The rest of it is just
beyond me.
She's an ISO.
KEVIN: Yeah. The last ISO.
SAM: All this time,
you were just protecting her.
(LAUGHS) Check that out.
She risked herself for me.
Some things are worth the risk.
KEVIN: Look at this.
Now, that is impressive
if I do say so myself. Huh?
Come on, it's gonna take a while
for her system to reboot.
CLU: The boy and Flynn are gone.
CASTOR: I presume, Your Excellency,
they perished in the elevator.
You presume?
Find them.
Cell phones, online dating, Wi-Fi.
- KEVIN: What's Wi-Fi?
- Wireless interlinking.
- Of digital devices?
- Yeah.
Hmm. I thought of that in '85.
(LAUGHS)
Mom and Dad are...
- I assume that...
- Yeah.
Oh.
Mac when I was 12
and Gram five years later.
You remember that night
when you didn't come home?
- Well...
- You said...
I said I'd show you the Grid.
You should have seen this place
back then.
I couldn't wait to show it to you.
Could not wait.
SAM: Must have been something
before Clu screwed it up.
No, no, he...
He's me. I screwed it up.
Chasing after perfection.
Chasing after
what was right in front of me.
Look what you've accomplished.
It's incredible.
Sam,
I'd have given it all up
for one more day with you.
(SIGHS)
Hey.
Remember your old Ducati?
You kidding? Not a day goes by
I don't think about that bike.
- Yeah, well, I'm fixing her up.
- You busted my bike?
Twenty years in the shed, no tarp.
I mean, she needed a little love.
(LAUGHS)
How does she run?
Well, when I'm done, better than ever.
Well, man, I'd like to see that.
You will.
Here.
She's rebooting. Give her this.
The old man's gonna knock on the sky,
listen to the sound.
I presume our
understanding is still valid?
A sizeable request, I know.
But seemingly fitting compensation.
Don't you think?
Just imagine the secrets it holds.
But there's something else, too.
Isn't there?
I've heard the chatter
about this private initiative.
I realize that our alliance is,
at times,
uneasy.
But always necessary.
You know you need me
right where I am.
Of course you're right.
Enjoy the drink.
(BEEPING)
(CLU LAUGHS)
- (GASPS)
- Hey. It's okay. We're safe for now.
We're heading east towards the portal.
Clu has the disk.
Once I get out, I can shut him down.
I should never have sent you to Zuse.
It was a mistake.
It's okay. I've made a few myself.
Where is he?
SAM: I think he's knocking on the sky.
QUORRA: And listening to the sound.
Yeah.
How did you find him?
It's okay.
I know.
QUORRA: It was during the Purge.
Clu was relentless.
The Black Guard were executing ISOs
in the streets.
Everyone I knew disappeared.
Then they came for me.
So I ran.
But soon they had me surrounded.
I prepared for the end.
And just as everything was going dark,
I felt a hand on my shoulder.
And when I opened my eyes,
standing above me was your father.
He saved me.
SAM: Hell of a view.
QUORRA: It used to let us know
that Flynn was here.
It became the symbol
of something bigger,
something better than this world.
I've never been this close before.
It's how I imagine a sunrise to be.
(QUORRA LAUGHS)
(RUMBLING)
Get below! Move!
This isn't supposed to be here.
What is this?
Clu can't create programs.
He can only destroy or repurpose them.
COMPUTER: Battalion 6,
report to Staging Area Alpha.
Let's go.
COMPUTER: All high-level functions,
report immediately to combat stations.
- Goodbye.
- Quorra!
- What's she doing?
- Removing herself from the equation.
Tron.
KEVIN: He's alive.
COMPUTER:
Throne ship is approaching.
- We can't just let her go.
- No, Sam, there's another way.
Throne ship is approaching.
JARVIS: I've never seen anything like it.
Humbly, sir, I know
you have greater designs
than any of us understand.
What does it do?
She's gonna wind up like one of them.
Keep moving, Sam.
(PROGRAMS CHANT)
You are a very rare bird,
aren't you, now?
Where's your disk?
Where is he?
It must have been so lonely out there.
How tragic to be the only one.
I've seen what users
are capable of, Clu.
You don't belong with them.
Take her upstairs.
And find them.
(PROGRAMS CHANT)
- Greetings, programs!
- (PROGRAMS CHEER)
- Kevin Flynn!
Where are you now?!?
(LAUGHS)
My fellow programs,
let there be no doubt
that our world is a cage no more.
For at this moment,
the key to the next frontier is finally
in our possession!
(PROGRAMS CHEER)
Your disk.
SAM: He's taking all of this with him.
He's figured out how to do it.
Dad, we have to get your disk.
We gotta get to the portal.
You shut them down outside.
Even if I make it out alive, you won't last in here.
KEVIN: Sam-
SAM: Quorra won't last!
KEVIN: Sam, it'll be alright. Come on!
SAM: Will you let it go?
I'm not going home without you!
I was afraid you were going to say that.
Meet me on the flight deck in five
and get us some wheels.
CLU: Maximize efficiency...
And unlike our selfish creator
who reserved the privilege of our world
all to himself,
I...
...will make their world open
CLU: To all of us!
(PROGRAMS CHEER)
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
(BEEPING)
SENTRY: Identify yourself, program.
(FAINT YELL)
(PROGRAMS CHANT)
Right away, sir.
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
(SHRIEKING)
COMPUTER: Master key disengaged.
Master key disengaged.
I came with a girl, a program.
Where is she?
Sam!
- Why are you here?
- We gotta get to the flight deck.
Clu will be here any minute,
we'll never make it!
Come on, kiddo.
Hurry!
Made it.
You've got this Quorra
COMPUTER: Light fighter 5.
Unauthorized launch.
Death to the user!
Light jets.
Here they come.
- Sam, take the turret.
- Huh?
SAM: Yeah!
Whooh!
- I don't think this is a good idea.
- You're probably right.
(ENGINE STOPS)
Tron.
Oh, come on.
CLU: Rinzler! Take the shot!
Finish the game!
TRON: I fight for the users.
(SCREAMS)
(LAUGHS)
This is mine.
I had a feeling you'd be here!
(LAUGHS) The cycles
haven't been kind, have they?
Oh, you don't look so bad.
I did everything.
Everything you ever asked.
I know you did.
- CLU: I executed the plan!
- As you saw it.
You... You promised that we
would change the world together.
- You broke your promise.
- I know.
I understand that now.
I took this system
to its maximum potential.
I created the perfect system!
The thing about perfection
is that it's unknowable.
You wouldn't know that
because I didn't when I created you.
I'm sorry, Clu.
I'm sorry.
(YELLS)
Go.
Clu!
Dad!
CLU: You knew I'd beat you.
And still you did all this? For him.
No.
No!
Why?
He's my son.
Go!
Sam! It's time!
Goodbye, kiddo.
(GROANS)
No!
SAM: Alan.
ALAN: You paged me?
Yeah.
I need you at ENCOM at 8:00 a.m.
I'm taking the company back, Alan.
You were right.
About what?
About everything.